Guide to the Julius Edelstein papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VI: Speeches, 1952-1957
  - Eastland Election to Chairmanship of the Senate Judiciary Committee, 1956 March 2 (Box 93, Folder 20)
  - Building and Construction Trades Conference, 1956 March 5 (Box 93, Folder 21)
  - Dairy Farmers, 1956 March 8 (Box 93, Folder 22)
  - The Cyprus Dilemma, 1956 March 13 (Box 93, Folder 23)
  - Resolution Calling for Self Determination for Cyprus, 1956 March 13 (Box 93, Folder 24)
  - Civil Rights Crisis, 1956 March 16 (Box 93, Folder 25)
  - New York State Committees Against Discrimination, 1956 March 17 (Box 93, Folder 26)
  - Democratic Party--Party for Young Americans, 1956 March 19 (Box 93, Folder 27)
  - National Banquet of the Order of the American Hellenic Educational Progressive Association (AHEPA), 1956 March 19 (Box 93, Folder 28)
  - Juvenile Delinquency Appropriation, 1956 March 21 (Box 93, Folder 29)
  - Proposed Constitutional Amendment on Election of President, 1956 March 21 (Box 93, Folder 30)
  - Greek Independence, 1956 March 23 (Box 93, Folder 31)
  - The Offshore Islands, 1956 March 23 (Box 93, Folder 32)
  - Lesson from Woodrow Wilson on Saudi Arabian Discrimination, 1956 March 26 (Box 93, Folder 33)
  - Testimony before the Housing Subcommittee, 1956 March 27 (Box 93, Folder 34)
  - Social Security, 1956 March 28 (Box 93, Folder 35)
  - Flood Danger in New York State, 1956 April 9 (Box 93, Folder 36)
  - Proposed Federal Commission on the Arts, 1956 April 9 (Box 93, Folder 37)
  - George Washington’s Letter to the Hebrew Congregation in Newport, Rhode Island, 1956 April 11 (Box 93, Folder 38)
  - Interview by James T. Farrell with Adlai Stevenson, 1956 April 11 (Box 93, Folder 39)
  - Flood Insurance Program Provisions, 1956 April 12 (Box 93, Folder 40)
  - Silver Anniversary Banquet of the National Housing Conference, 1956 April 12 (Box 93, Folder 41)
  - Parcel Post Rates Reduction for Relief Packages, 1956 April 13 (Box 93, Folder 42)
  - Urging Shipment of Arms to Israel, 1956 April 13 (Box 93, Folder 43)
  - Camp Drum, New York, 1956 April 14 (Box 93, Folder 44)
  - Federal Commission on the Arts, 1956 April 14 (Box 93, Folder 45)
  - Farm Bill, 1956 April 16 (Box 93, Folder 46)
  - Israel Independence Day, 1956 April 16 (Box 93, Folder 47)
  - Continuing Battle for Freedom, 1956 April 17 (Box 93, Folder 48)
  - Acceptance of Citizenship Award from the Albert Einstein College of Medicine, 1956 April 18 (Box 93, Folder 49)
  - Need for Federal Action on Narcotics Problem, 1956 April 19 (Box 93, Folder 50)
  - Acceptance of the Twentieth Anniversary Freedom Award, 1956 April 22 (Box 93, Folder 51)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution Opposing Resolution on McCarran-Walter Act, 1956 April 24 (Box 93, Folder 52)
  - Federal Flood Insurance Act of 1956 1956 April 30 (Box 93, Folder 53)
  - Julius C. C. Edelstein in Panel Debate on Immigration Law, 1956 May 1 (Box 93, Folder 54)
  - Radio TV News clip on Niagara Bill, 1956 May 1 (Box 93, Folder 55)
  - Polish Constitution Day, 1956 May 3 (Box 93, Folder 56)
  - Annual Dinner Sponsored by Bronx County Democratic Committee, 1956 May 4 (Box 93, Folder 57)
  - Cornerstone Laying Ceremony, B’nai B’rith, 1956 May 6 (Box 93, Folder 58)
  - Sidney Hatkin Security Case, 1956 May 7 (Box 93, Folder 59)
  - Social Security Amendment--Tips and Gratuities, 1956 May 7 (Box 93, Folder 60)
  - Buffalo Port Dredging--North Channel, 1956 May 8 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Upper Susquehanna Dams, 1956 May 8 (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Federal Flood Insurance Act, 1956 May 10 (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Kings County Democratic Dinner, 1956 May 10 (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Floor Remarks on Niagara Bill, 1956 May 14 (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - War Orphans Educational Assistance Bills, 1956 May 14 (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Niagara Bill Prior to Recommittal Vote, 1956 May 16 (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - 100th Anniversary of the Founding of Vassar College, 1956 May 16 (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Acceptance of the Philip Murray Award of the NAACP, 1956 May 18 (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - Electric Consumers Conference, 1956 May 20 (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - Amendment of the Civil Service Retirement Act, 1956 May 21 (Box 94, Folder 11)
  - Twentieth Biennial Convention of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1956 May 21 (Box 94, Folder 12)
  - The Future of Middle Income Housing, 1956 May 24 (Box 94, Folder 13)
  - Housing Bill, 1956 May 24 (Box 94, Folder 14)
  - Narcotics Bill, 1956 May 25 (Box 94, Folder 15)
  - Highway Bill, 1956 May 28 (Box 94, Folder 16)
  - War Orphans Educational Assistance Bill, 1956 May 28 (Box 94, Folder 17)
  - Urban League of Greater New York, 1956 June 3 (Box 94, Folder 18)
  - Civil Rights--A Nationwide Problem, 1956 June 4 (Box 94, Folder 19)
  - 12th Annual Dinner of the Liberal Party, 1956 June 13 (Box 94, Folder 20)
  - Draft Letter to New York State Members of Congress, 1956 June 14 (Box 94, Folder 21)
  - Request for House Action on Niagara Bill, 1956 June 15 (Box 94, Folder 22)
  - New Animal Disease Laboratory, 1956 June 18 (Box 94, Folder 23)
  - Draft on Sheepherder’s Bill, 1956 June 19 (Box 94, Folder 24)
  - Press Conference on the Arrival of Grace Li in Washington, DC, 1956 June 19 (Box 94, Folder 25)
  - Pending Sheepherder’s Bill, 1956 June 20 (Box 94, Folder 26)
  - Veterans Loan Guaranty Program, 1956 June 20 (Box 94, Folder 27)
  - Anti-Segregation Amendment to School Aid Bill, 1956 June 25 (Box 94, Folder 28)
  - Resolution on Discrimination by Saudi Arabia, 1956 June 27 (Box 94, Folder 29)
  - Public Works Committee Action on Reporting the Niagara Bill, 1956 June 29 (Box 94, Folder 30)
  - 15th Anniversary of the Death of Paderewski, 1956 June 30 (Box 94, Folder 31)
  - Judicial Machinery Improvements, 1956 July 5 (Box 94, Folder 32)
  - Series of Washington Farm Reporter Transcripts, 1956 July 12 (Box 94, Folder 33)
  - Testimony on Pending Civil Rights Bill, 1956 July 12 (Box 94, Folder 34)
  - Nomination of Simon E. Sobeloff to Circuit Court of Appeals, 1956 July 16 (Box 94, Folder 35)
  - Radio Report on Juvenile Delinquency Bill, 1956 July 16 (Box 94, Folder 36)
  - Pending Legislation to Amend the Social Security Act, 1956 July 16-17 (Box 94, Folder 37)
  - Hells Canyon Dam Project, 1956 July 18 (Box 94, Folder 38)
  - Public Assistance Program in the Virgin Islands, 1956 July 18 (Box 94, Folder 39)
  - Social Security Amendment--Child Welfare Services, 1956 July 18 (Box 94, Folder 40)
  - Mansfield-Lehman Amendment--UN Technical Aid Program, 1956 July 19 (Box 94, Folder 41)
  - Congressional Action on Juvenile Delinquency and Child Welfare, 1956 July 21 (Box 94, Folder 42)
  - Proposed Amendments to Immigration Act, 1956 July 22 (Box 94, Folder 43)
  - Asks for Study of Corporate Proxy Practices, 1956 July 23 (Box 94, Folder 44)
  - Testimony Before Foreign Relations Committee on Saudi Arabian Discrimination, 1956 July 23 (Box 94, Folder 45)
  - Radio Recording on Civil Rights, 1956 July 25 (Box 94, Folder 46)
  - Amendment to Pending Immigration Bill, 1956 July 26 (Box 94, Folder 47)
  - Failure to Pass Legislation--Niagara Bill, 1956 July 30 (Box 94, Folder 48)
  - Seizure of Suez Canal by Egypt, 1956 July 31 (Box 94, Folder 49)
  - White House Listing of Niagara Bill is “Political Hypocrisy”, 1956 August 2 (Box 94, Folder 50)
  - Civil Rights Testimony Before the Platform Committee of the DNC, 1956 August 10 (Box 94, Folder 51)
  - National Convention of AHEPA, 1956 August 15 (Box 94, Folder 52)
  - Support of Minority Report on Civil Rights, 1956 August 15 (Box 94, Folder 53)
  - Seconding Nomination of Adlai Stevenson, 1956 August 16 (Box 94, Folder 54)
  - Candidacy for Re-election to the US Senate, 1956 August 21 (Box 94, Folder 55)
  - Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO) Council Convention, 1956 August 23 (Box 94, Folder 56)
  - Nominating Mayor Robert Wagner for US Senator, 1956 September 10 (Box 94, Folder 57)
  - Liberal Party Rally, 1956 September 11 (Box 94, Folder 58)
  - Statement on Comments of Senator Prescott Bush, 1956 October 3 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Delancy Street Remarks, 1956 October 4 (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Harlem Rally, 1956 October 4 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Statement on Remarks on Civil Rights by Howard Pyle, 1956 October 8 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Chwastov Case, 1956 October 9-10 (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Saudi Arabian Discrimination Against American GI’s, 1956 October 10 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Discrimination Against Negro Service Personnel in Use of Defense Funds, 1956 October 11 (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Statement on Javits on Immigration, 1956 October 13 (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Rallies in Nassau County, 1956 October 15 (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - Urge to Move Mitchel Air Force Base Activities, 1956 October 15 (Box 95, Folder 10)
  - Broadcast over WABC TV, “Middle East and Civil Rights”, 1956 October 17 (Box 95, Folder 11)
  - Levittown Rally, 1956 October 18 (Box 95, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn Message, 1956 October 19 (Box 95, Folder 13)
  - Rockland County Rally, 1956 October 19 (Box 95, Folder 14)
  - Washington Square Youth Rally--Not Delivered, 1956 October 19 (Box 95, Folder 15)
  - American-Hungarian Rally, 1956 October 21 (Box 95, Folder 16)
  - Anniversary of the Birth of Franz Liszt, 1956 October 22 (Box 95, Folder 17)
  - Lexington Democratic Club, 1956 October 22 (Box 95, Folder 18)
  - Madison Square Garden Rally, 1956 October 23 (Box 95, Folder 19)
  - Bronx Rally, 1956 October 24 (Box 95, Folder 20)
  - Liberal Party Women’s Campaign Committee, 1956 October 24 (Box 95, Folder 21)
  - Statement on Javits, 1956 October 25 (Box 95, Folder 22)
  - Workmen’s Circle Meeting, 1956 October 25 (Box 95, Folder 23)
  - Harrison, NY Rally, 1956 October 27 (Box 95, Folder 24)
  - Hartsdale School, 1956 October 27 (Box 95, Folder 25)
  - Rye, NY Rally, 1956 October 27 (Box 95, Folder 26)
  - Housing Speech, 1956 October 28 (Box 95, Folder 27)
  - Luncheon in Senator Lehman’s Honor by Nationalities Division, 1956 October 28 (Box 95, Folder 28)
  - Cutters Union, 1956 October 29 (Box 95, Folder 29)
  - Vassar Hall Political Rally, 1956 October 29 (Box 95, Folder 30)
  - Discontinuation of Segregation in Army’s Off-duty Education Program, 1956 October 30 (Box 95, Folder 31)
  - Washington Heights Liberal Party Rally, 1956 October 30 (Box 95, Folder 32)
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers Union, 1956 October 31 (Box 95, Folder 33)
  - Garment Center, 1956 October 31 (Box 95, Folder 34)
  - Introduction of Mayor at Women’s Luncheon for Stevenson, 1956 November (Box 95, Folder 35)
  - Columbia University Rally, 1956 November 1 (Box 95, Folder 36)
  - Harlem 1st Voter Dance Rally, 1956 November 1 (Box 95, Folder 37)
  - Manhattan Center Rally for Robert Wagner, 1956 November 1 (Box 95, Folder 38)
  - Pressers Union, 1956 November 1 (Box 95, Folder 39)
  - Radio Address, “The Truth About Civil Rights”, 1956 November 1 (Box 95, Folder 40)
  - Five Counties Rally, 1956 November 2 (Box 95, Folder 41)
  - Fur Workers Rally, 1956 November 2 (Box 95, Folder 42)
  - Rivington and Pitt Streets Rally, 1956 November 2 (Box 95, Folder 43)
  - United Labor Committee Rally, 1956 November 2 (Box 95, Folder 44)
  - Statement on Governor Stevenson’s Proposal for UN to Hungary, 1956 November 4 (Box 95, Folder 45)
  - Yonkers Reception and Rally, 1956 November 4 (Box 95, Folder 46)
  - Radio Address--Draft, Not Delivered, 1956 November 5 (Box 95, Folder 47)
  - Radio Address on Liberal Party Program, 1956 November 6 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Situation in Middle East, 1956 November 14 (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Address to the B’nai Jeshurun Congregation, 1956 November 22 (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Anti-Defamation League of B’nai B’rith, 1956 November 24 (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Weizmann Dinner--Weizmann Institute of Science, 1956 November 27 (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Washington Hebrew Congregation, 1956 December 7 (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Murray-Green Award of the AFL-CIO--Acceptance, 1956 December 11 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Hadassah Newsletter --“Prospects, Problems and Issues Confronting the 85th Congress”, 1956 December 28 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - New Senate Rules, 1956 December 30 (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - Farewell Letter, 1957 January 3 (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - Lexington Democratic Club, 1957 January 18 (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - Speech by Adlai Stevenson in San Francisco, 1957 February 2 (Box 96, Folder 12)
  - Western Democratic Conference Session on Human Resources, 1957 February 15 (Box 96, Folder 13)
  - National Council of Jewish Women, 1957 March 21 (Box 96, Folder 14)
  - City College Baruch School of Business, 1957 April 2 (Box 96, Folder 15)
  - Albany Jewish Welfare Fund, 1957 April 9 (Box 96, Folder 16)
  - American Jewish Committee’s 50th Anniversary Observance, 1957 April 10 (Box 96, Folder 17)
  - Luncheon for Louise Waterman Wise Youth Center Sponsored by the American Jewish Congress, 1957 April 10 (Box 96, Folder 18)
  - Acceptance of the Social Justice Award of the Religion and Labor Foundation, 1957 April 24 (Box 96, Folder 19)
  - Keynote Address at the Seventh Annual Conference of Alumni Association of the New York School of Social Work. 1957 April 27 (Box 96, Folder 20)
  - Acceptance of Award at the International Leadership Mobilzation for American Reform Judaism, 1957 May 1 (Box 96, Folder 21)
  - Temple Israel Brotherhood in Boston, 1957 May 14 (Box 96, Folder 22)
  - Dinner in Honor of Robert Wagner, 1957 May 20 (Box 96, Folder 23)
  - Acceptance of the Solomon Bublick Public Service Award, 1957 October 6 (Box 96, Folder 24)
  - Rally for Hungarian Peoples, 1957 December 30 (Box 96, Folder 25)
- Series VII: Subject Files, 1917-1958 (1948-1953)
  The materials found in this series include memoranda, speeches, referenda, statistics, clippings, press releases, and government documents directly linked to the subject of a current, pending or ongoing legislative matter. The prominent subjects are: agriculture, civil liberties, civil rights, civil service, dairy industry, defense, education, foreign policy and aid, health, housing, immigration including the NCIC, internal security bill, labor, New York State government, local and national politics, Niagara and Saint Lawrence power projects, social security and welfare, tidelands, taxes and veterans. The topical arrangement established by Edelstein has been maintained.
  - Agriculture--General, 1950-1952, 1955, (2 Folders) (Box 96, Folder 26-27)
  - Agriculture
    - 50/50 Amendment--Alien Property, 1953, 1956 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Migratory Labor, 1951 (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Parity, 1951 (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Armed Forces--General, 1950, 1952 (Folder 4)
    - Use of US Troops Abroad, 1951 (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - Unification, 1952 (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - Veterans, 1949-1952, (2 Folders) (Box 97, Folder 7-8)
  - Atom Bomb--General, 1951, 1954-1955 (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - Catholics--General, 1949-1950 (Box 97, Folder 10)
  - Civil Liberties--General, 1940, 1943, 1950-1953, (2 Folders) (Box 97, Folder 11-12)
  - Civil Liberties
    - Government Loyalty Program, 1948-1952 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Internal Security, 1950-1951 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Recording Jury Proceedings, 1955 (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Rules of Fair Committee Procedure, 1954, undated (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Civil Rights--General, 1947, 1949-1953, 1956, undated, (4 Folders) (Box 98, Folder 5-8)
  - Civil Rights
    - Armed Forces, 1950-1955, undated, (4 Folders) (Box 99, Folder 1-4)
    - Cloture, 1948-1953, (4 Folders) (Box 99, Folder 5-8)
    - Cloture, 1950-1952 (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Education, 1951-1952 (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - Fair Employment Practices, 1947, 1949-1953, (2 Folders) (Box 100, Folder 3-4)
    - New York State, 1945-1950, 1952, (2 Folders) (Box 100, Folder 5-6)
    - Political, 1950-1952 (Box 100, Folder 7)
    - Political, 1952 (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - State and Local, 1949-1952, (2 Folders) (Box 101, Folder 2-3)
  - Civil Service--General, 1951 (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Coal--General, 1950-1956 (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - Congress
    - General, 1950-1956 (Box 101, Folder 6)
    - Congressional Salaries, 1954-1955 (Box 101, Folder 7)
    - Record of, 1947-1953 (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - Crime--General, 1950-1951 (Box 101, Folder 9)
  - Dairy Industry--General, 1953, 1955 (Box 101, Folder 10)
  - District of Columbia--General, 1951 (Box 101, Folder 11)
  - Economic and Fiscal Policy--General, 1950-1951 (Box 101, Folder 12)
  - Economic and Fiscal Policy
    - Appropriations, 1950-1951 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, 1950-1951 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Budget and Defense Spending, 1950-1952 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Economic Conditions, 1950, 1952-1953, (2 Folders) (Box 102, Folder 4-5)
    - Emergency Controls, 1950-1953 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Information from the New York State Bar Association, undated (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Monopoly, 1949-1952 (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - Taxation, 1950-1951 (Box 102, Folder 9)
    - Taxation, 1950-1952, (2 Folders) (Box 103, Folder 1-2)
      - Tax Bill of 1951, 1951 (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Education
    - General, 1950-1952, 1955, (2 Folders) (Box 103, Folder 4-5)
    - Adult, 1952 (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - Vocational, 1950 (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Equal Rights for Women--General, 1945, 1948-1953 (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Ethics in Government--General, 1951-1952 (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Fair Trade--General, 1951-1952 (Box 103, Folder 10)
  - Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)--General, 1950-1951, 1955 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Foreign Aid
    - General, 1950-1952, 1955-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 104, Folder 2-3)
    - European Recovery Program (ERP), 1950-1951, (3 Folders) (Box 104, Folder 4-6)
    - Mutual Security Act of 1955, 1951-1953, 1955, (2 Folders) (Box 104, Folder 7-8)
    - Point Four, 1949-1951 (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - Point Four, 1949-1953, (3 Folders) (Box 105, Folder 1-3)
  - Foreign Policy
    - General, 1949-1955, (2 Folders) (Box 105, Folder 4-5)
    - Africa, 1951-1952 (Box 105, Folder 6)
    - Anti-Semitism, 1952-1953 (Box 105, Folder 7)
    - Armenians, 1954 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Asia
      - General, 1950-1955 (Box 106, Folder 2)
      - China, 1948-1952, (2 Folders) (Box 106, Folder 3-4)
      - Formosa, 1950-1951, 1955 (Box 106, Folder 5)
      - India, 1950-1952 (Box 106, Folder 6)
      - Japan, 1950-1952 (Box 106, Folder 7)
      - Korea, 1950-1952 (Box 106, Folder 8)
      - Philippines, 1950-1952 (Box 106, Folder 9)
      - Philippines, 1942, 1947, 1949-1952, (2 Folders) (Box 107, Folder 1-2)
    - Atlantic Union and World Federation, 1949-1950, (2 Folders) (Box 107, Folder 3-4)
    - Communism Abroad, 1948-1952 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Customs Simplification Bill, 1955 (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - Czechoslovakia and Bulgaria, 1951-1952 (Box 107, Folder 7)
    - Europe
      - Eastern, 1947-1952, (2 Folders) (Box 107, Folder 8-9)
      - Northern, 1952 (Box 107, Folder 10)
      - Southern, 1950, 1952, 1955 (Box 108, Folder 1)
      - Western, 1951-1952, 1954 (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - Germany
      - Booklets, 1949-1951 (Box 108, Folder 3)
      - Clippings, 1950, undated (Box 108, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 108, Folder 5)
      - Restitution, 1951 (Box 108, Folder 6)
      - State Department, 1949-1950 (Box 108, Folder 7)
      - Statements, 1948, 1950-1952, (2 Folders) (Box 108, Folder 8-9)
      - War Criminals, 1951, 1955-1956 (Box 108, Folder 10)
    - Hungary and Ukraine, 1950 (Box 108, Folder 11)
    - Information Program, 1950-1951 (Box 108, Folder 12)
    - Iran and Saudi Arabia, 1951, 1956 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - Israel, 1950-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 109, Folder 2-3)
    - Jerusalem, 1949-1950 (Box 109, Folder 4)
    - Lithuania and Romania, 1951-1954 (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - Nationality in the US, 1950-1952 (Box 109, Folder 6)
    - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), 1949-1952 (Box 109, Folder 7)
    - Near East--Arab-Israeli Relationship, 1950-1952, 1955 (Box 109, Folder 8)
    - Peace Proposals, 1950 (Box 109, Folder 9)
    - Poland, 1950-1952 (Box 109, Folder 10)
    - Soviet Union, 1947, 1949-1952 (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - Spain, 1950-1951 (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - Tariffs, 1950-1956 (Box 110, Folder 3-4)
    - United Kingdom, 1950-1951 (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - United Nations (UN)
      - General, 1950-1952 (Box 110, Folder 6-7)
      - Genocide--Includes Photographs, 1948-1950 (Box 110, Folder 8)
      - Genocide, 1949-1950, 1953, 1955 (Box 111, Folder 1)
      - Human Rights, 1950-1952 (Box 111, Folder 2)
      - Bank for Reconstruction and Development, 1950-1951 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - Yugoslavia, 1953 (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - Health
    - General, 1934, 1949-1951 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - Aid to Medical Education, 1951, (2 Folders) (Box 111, Folder 6-7)
    - Appropriations, 1950-1954 (Box 111, Folder 8)
    - Bills, 1949-1950, 1954, (2 Folders) (Box 112, Folder 1-2)
    - Clark Report, 1951 (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence and Clippings, 1950-1951 (Box 112, Folder 4)
    - Emergency Maternal and Infant Care Program (EMIC), 1951-1952 (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - Health Commission, 1952 (Box 112, Folder 6)
    - Industrial Safety Bill, 1952 (Box 112, Folder 7)
    - Insurance,1946-1947 1949-1951, 1955, (2 Folders) (Box 112, Folder 8-9)
    - Lehman, Herbert H., 1950 (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - Old Age Survivors Insurance System (OASI)--Hospital Insurance, 1951-1952 (Box 113, Folder 2)
    - Pure Food and Drugs, 1951 (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - Statements and Memorandums, 1949-1950, (2 Folders) (Box 113, Folder 4-5)
    - Western Medical Corporation, 1951-1952 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Housing
    - General, 1950-1952, 1955-1956 (Box 113, Folder 7)
    - New York State, 1951-1952, 1954-1955 (Box 113, Folder 8)
    - Rent Gouging of Military Personnel, 1951 (Box 113, Folder 9)
  - Immigration
    - General, 1952-1957 (Box 113, Folder 10)
    - Campaign Material, 1952 (Box 113, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1955-1956 (Box 113, Folder 12)
      - National Committee on Immigration and Citizenship (NCIC), 1952-1956 (Box 113, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence (Box 114)
      - National Committee on Immigration and Citizenship (NCIC), 1952-1956, (5 Folders) (Box 114, Folder 1-5)
    - Emergency Legislation, 1951-1952 (Box 114, Folder 6)
    - Lehman, Herbert H.--Speeches and Remarks, 1952 (Box 114, Folder 7)
    - McCarran-Walter Bill
      - General, 1951-1952, 1956 (Box 114, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 1950-1953, (2 Folders) (Box 115, Folder 1-2)
      - Hardship Cases, 1951-1952 (Box 115, Folder 3)
      - Interpreter Releases, 1953-1954, (2 Folders) (Box 115, Folder 4-5)
      - Legal Background, 1951-1952 (Box 116, Folder 1)
      - Mailing Lists, 1951-1952 (Box 116, Folder 2)
      - Organizational Memorandums, 1951-1952, (3 Folders) (Box 116, Folder 3-5)
      - Press Comments, 1952 (Box 116, Folder 6)
      - Proposed Amendments, 1952 (Box 116, Folder 7)
      - Proposed Amendments, 1952 (Box 117, Folder 1)
      - Lehman-Humphrey Bill--Summaries and Comparisons, 1952 (Box 117, Folder 2)
      - Lehman-Humphrey Bill--Supporting Organizations, 1952 (Box 117, Folder 3)
      - Supporting Organizations, 1951-1952 (Box 117, Folder 4)
      - Voting Data, 1952 (Box 117, Folder 5)
    - President’s Commission on Immigration and Naturalization, 1952 (Box 117, Folder 6)
    - Refugee Problem, 1950, 1953 (Box 117, Folder 7)
    - Speech Drafts, 1952, undated (Box 117, Folder 8)
    - Speech Drafts, 1952-1954 (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Statistics, 1940, 1950-1952 (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - Surplus Populations, 1951-1952 (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - Indians
    - General, 1949-1952 (Box 118, Folder 4)
    - Attorney Contracts, 1951-1953, (2 Folders) (Box 118, Folder 5-6)
    - Bills--General, 1944-1954 (Box 118, Folder 7)
    - Bills (Box 119)
      - General, 1944-1954 (Box 119, Folder 1)